<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?><feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'><title>Frank's Book Log</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/feed.xml' rel='self' /><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com' /><updated>2014-10-11T22:23:37-04:00</updated><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com</id><author><name>Frank Showalter</name></author><entry><title>33. Dark Mountain by Richard Laymon ★★★☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/dark-mountain-by-richard-laymon' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/dark-mountain-by-richard-laymon</id><updated>2014-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Two families go camping in the California mountains. They cross paths with a backwoods witch and her murderous son. They kill the son and escape but not before the old woman puts a curse on them. The families return home, eager to put the horrific trip behind them, but strange things start happening. Small things at first. One slips in the shower. Another gets cramps in both legs while swimming in the pool. But soon, the coincidences begin to pile up. People end up in the hospital. Or worse. Soon, the remaining unharmed members travel back to the mountains to deal with the witch and remove the curse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laymon&amp;rsquo;s twelth published novel is his most ambitious yet in terms of cast. There are twelve principal characters and Laymon shifts between eight of them to tell the story. There&amp;rsquo;s a classic Laymon sequence to open the story where we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to the witch and her son, but then it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a jumble as he brings in the two families. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd that the two families would be close enough to vacation together, yet their teenage children wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know each other. Anyway, things smooth out once Laymon gets the characters introduced and into the woods. It&amp;rsquo;s a cliched setup (hikers stalked by mountain psychos) but Laymon uses it to engender us to some of the characters, and it &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; pays off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second half the setting shifts back to suburban Los Angeles. We&amp;rsquo;re no longer in a predictable setup. The curse takes effect, winnowing the cast. There&amp;rsquo;s a well-done scene involving two teens on a first date that ranks among Laymon&amp;rsquo;s best to date. While Laymon may have overextended himself in the first half, he seems much more comfortable in the second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as good as the second half is, it can&amp;rsquo;t quite justify the first. Some characters never pay off. Flash&amp;rsquo;s wife and twin daughters are underdeveloped. The cousin feels like a plot convienience. And the mountain witch and her son are forgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dark Mountain&lt;/em&gt; feels like an exercise for Laymon. He takes what is, for him, a familiar plot, and stretches himself by writing from a larger number of viewpoints with a larger cast of characters. For fans of the author it may be an interesting look into his development as a writer, but others would do well to skip it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>32. Peter Cushing: A Life in Film by David Miller ★★★☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/peter-cushing-a-life-in-film-by-david-miller' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/peter-cushing-a-life-in-film-by-david-miller</id><updated>2014-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Cushing: A Life in Film&lt;/em&gt; chronicles the horror icon&amp;rsquo;s life via his appearances on stage and screen. Biographer David Miller&amp;rsquo;s focus on Cushing&amp;rsquo;s professional life differentiates this work from Cushing&amp;rsquo;s two autobiographies. Miller&amp;rsquo;s disciplined approach feels, at times, less like the story of Cushing&amp;rsquo;s life, and more like a reference guide to his career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing. Among the better tidbits: Cushing came close enough to starring in Lucio Fulci&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;The Black Cat (&amp;lt;&amp;gt;)&lt;/em&gt; to have annotated the script with notes on his performance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miller&amp;rsquo;s research is thorough, and he likes to show it. But do we really care about the exact dates that the play &amp;lt;&amp;gt;, with Cushing as &amp;lt;&amp;gt;, opened and closed? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, fair warning: there&amp;rsquo;s little sympathy for readers outside the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit to having to look up what &amp;lt;&amp;gt; meant. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t he have just said &amp;lsquo;bingo&amp;rsquo;? &lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>31. Creepshow by Stephen King ★★★☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/creepshow-by-stephen-king' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/creepshow-by-stephen-king</id><updated>2014-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creepshow&lt;/em&gt; is a comic book adaptaion of the film of the same name. Illustrated by Bernie Wrightson, the book, like the film,  is a homage to the EC Comics publications of the 50s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five stores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Father&amp;rsquo;s Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first story sees the patriarch of a disfunctional, money-grubbing family rise from the grave to avenge his murder at the hands of his daughter. It&amp;rsquo;s a little dialog-heavy for a visual format, but it does a good job setting the tone for the rest of the stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Lonesome Death of Jordy Verrill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second story follows Jordy Verrill, a country yokel who discovers a small meteorite in his yard. Jordy, of course, messess with the smouldering rock and it cracks open, splashing him with a glowing green substance.  Soon Jordy&amp;rsquo;s covered in a strange alien moss. The itching is unbearable. Somehow, he knows a bath will releave the irritation, but his last shred of good sense manifests in the form of the ghost of his dead father, who warns him that whatever&amp;rsquo;s growing on him needs water to survive. Jordy takes the bath anyway. By the next moring Jordy and his farm are covered in the alien vegitation. Jordy commits suicide even as we see the weather forecast of heavy rains. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an adaptation of the uncollected short story &amp;ldquo;Weeds,&amp;rdquo; by King.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Crate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third story, like the first is a little talky for a visual medium. While it played well in the movie, comic adaptation is a bit stiff. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot concerns a college professor, Dexter Stanley who finds a crate in the college basement that seems to have been forgotten about some hundred and fifty years prior. Inside is a ferocious creature that kills a janitor and grad student before 
Dexter flees for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dexter turns to his friend, fellow professor Henry Northrup. Northrup sees an opportuntiy to rid himself of his abusive, cheating wife. The creature obliges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Something to Tide You Over&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forth story is the best of the bunch. A wealthy man, Richard Vickers, discovers his wife has been cheating on him and concocts a terrible revenge. Outside his isolated beach house, Vickers buries his wife&amp;rsquo;s lover up to his neck just outside the incoming surf. The tide is coming in will push up well past the man&amp;rsquo;s head. How long can you hold your breath?, asks Vickers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making things even more ghastly, Vickers hauls out a small television on which he plays back footage of his wife meeting her end in a similar manner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vickers retires to his beach house to watch the proceedings via closed-circuit television. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, he returns to recover the bodies but they&amp;rsquo;re nowhere to be found. Telling himself that the tide must have taken them, he returns home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that night, the two lovers return as undead monsters covered in seaweed. Vickers tries to shoot them, but as they say, &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t kill someone if they&amp;rsquo;re already dead!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re Creeping Up on You!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final story is the only one that actually plays better as a comic. The plot concerns a Howard Hughes-esque businessman named Upson Pratt. As thunderstorms bummet&amp;lt;?&amp;gt; the city, Pratt notices the impossible in his meticulously maintained fortress-like apartment penthouse. Roaches. He sprays and swears that someone will lose thier job for the idignity. But even as Pratt orchestrates a rutheless hostile takeover via a conference call, we see more roaches. Soon the thunderstorm triggers a rolling blackout and the roaches appear en mass. They swarm him, covering him, spilling into his mouth, down his throat. Come morning there isn&amp;rsquo;t a roach in sight, just Pratt&amp;rsquo;s bloated corpse. Then Pratt&amp;rsquo;s lips begin to move. And out comes a roach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While King isn&amp;rsquo;t a master of the medium, his stories certainly capture the spirit of the old horror comics. Fans of those books will enjoy &lt;em&gt;Creepshow&lt;/em&gt; but for more casual King fans, the movie is probably a better choice. &lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>30. The Dark Tower: The Gunslinger by Stephen King ★★★★☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-dark-tower-the-gunslinger-by-stephen-king' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-dark-tower-the-gunslinger-by-stephen-king</id><updated>2014-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'></content></entry><entry><title>29. The Intruder by Richard Laymon ★★★☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-intruder-by-richard-laymon' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-intruder-by-richard-laymon</id><updated>2014-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;The sound of breaking glass wakes Goldie. It&amp;rsquo;s dark. She hears footsteps in the hall. Heavy breathing. Someone&amp;rsquo;s in the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Intruder&lt;/em&gt; is another of Laymon&amp;rsquo;s entries in the FastBack series of books.  The books were small&amp;ndash;about the size of a passport&amp;ndash;and just under 30 pages. With a focus on action and a low vocabulary, the series strove to foster an interest in reading for pleasure in young adults. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a plot twist here that Laymon cannibalized for his later novel, &lt;em&gt;No Sanctuary&lt;/em&gt;. But it&amp;rsquo;s a good twist, even if I did see it coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>28. The Beast House by Richard Laymon </title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-beast-house-by-richard-laymon' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-beast-house-by-richard-laymon</id><updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'></content></entry><entry><title>27. The Last Hand by Richard Laymon ★★☆☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-last-hand-by-richard-laymon' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-last-hand-by-richard-laymon</id><updated>2014-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Brad Conroy is a secret agent coming off a botched assignment in New York City. His mission now is to deliver a black case in San Francisco. It&amp;rsquo;s his second chance. He knows there won&amp;rsquo;t be a third. But en route to meeting his contact, Brad spies a woman in trouble on the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Last Hand&lt;/em&gt; is another of Laymon’s entries in the FastBack series of books. The books were small–about the size of a passport–and just under 30 pages. With a focus on action and a low vocabulary, the series strove to foster an interest in reading for pleasure in young adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the FastBack entries I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far, this is the weakest. The obligatory twist ending feels contrived, and Brad spends a lot of time in his own head making for a slow read even at 28 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>26. The Running Man by Stephen King </title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-running-man-by-stephen-king' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/the-running-man-by-stephen-king</id><updated>2014-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'></content></entry><entry><title>25. Beware by Richard Laymon ★★★☆☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/beware-by-richard-laymon' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/beware-by-richard-laymon</id><updated>2014-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;Lacey is a reporter for the local paper in her small home town of Oasis, Arizona. A series of events sees her sexually assaulted and held hostage by an invisible assailant who seems to be someone from her past. Lacey makes an ingenious escape and skips town to hide out in a resort hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There she meets Scott, an author of pulp detective stories. He susses out that&amp;rsquo;s she&amp;rsquo;s in hiding and agrees to help her, even if he doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe her story about an invisible man. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few pages later, Lacey and Scott are running for their lives through the hotel&amp;rsquo;s corridors. Her invisible attacker has found her, but not before Scott had time to call in reinforcements. Matt Dukane, an elite mercenary and the source of Scott&amp;rsquo;s lurid tales, arrives via his private plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dukane meets up with Lacey and Scott, and the three soon realize they&amp;rsquo;re under attack from a mysterious cult. One that&amp;rsquo;s already infiltrated all levels of society and will stop at nothing until they&amp;rsquo;re all dead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beware&lt;/em&gt; is a nice return to the supernatural for Laymon. As is typical, he throws us into Lacey&amp;rsquo;s situation and floors the accelerator. We never get the full picture of the cult, just enough information to give us an idea of the stakes at play. The characters are thin but entertaining. You root for the good guys and loath the bad guys.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sexual assaults on Lacey can make for some tough reading, but they&amp;rsquo;re not gratuitous. Laymon uses the attacks to define Lacey, not as a victim, but as a strong-willed, quick-witted survivor.  For as much as his novels get labeled as misogynistic, it&amp;rsquo;s astounding how so many miss this point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything from Laymon thus far, this is pure pulp. An easy, fast read that keeps you hoping the characters survive every turn of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>24. Cujo by Stephen King ★★★★☆</title><link href='http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/cujo-by-stephen-king' /><id>http://booklog.frankshowalter.com/reviews/cujo-by-stephen-king</id><updated>2014-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><content type='html'>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cujo&lt;/em&gt; follows the Trenton family. They&amp;rsquo;re recent transplants from New York City to the small town of Castle Rock, Maine. Father Vic is an ad-man who’s forced to travel to New York for a couple of weeks leaving mother Donna and son Tad at home. Donna’s been having car trouble and Vic urges her to take her car to Joe Camber, a mechanic who lives on the outskirts of town. Donna and Tad make the journey not knowing the Camber family have all departed. Donna and Tad arrive only to have the car die, stranding them on the Camber’s driveway where they&amp;rsquo;re terrorized by the Camber’s 200lb St. Bernard, Cujo, who’s gone rabid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first read &lt;em&gt;Cujo&lt;/em&gt; when I was thirteen or fourteen. I went in expecting some kind of possessed demon-dog and when Cujo turned out to just be rabid, I felt let down. Reading it now, I can see that in keeping it grounded with a real monster King could delivery a real ending, his best one so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that King doesn’t intone that there are supernatural goings-on. The only plot King has to worry about is getting Donna and Tad to the Camber’s, but this involves a series of compounding circumstances. We accept them because in King’s hands Castle Rock itself becomes a central character, one with, lets say, an ‘inclination’ toward evil. If one were to look at the infant mortality rate across Maine, one would suspect it would be a point or so higher in Castle Rock. The kind of thing most would dismiss as part of the ‘margin for error’ in the sampling, but we know better. King makes it clear that Cujo isn’t a bad dog, just one unfortunate enough to catch rabies because, well, that’s what Castle Rock does to good things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vic is a successful advertising executive and family man facing the collapse of his firm and marriage. Donna is a doting mother carrying on an affair with the local tennis pro. Joe Camber is an honest mechanic but a mean drunk well his way to being an alcoholic. Charity is Joe’s dutiful wife who dreams of running away. Free from plot, King dives deep into the hidden side of bucolic small-town life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great meditation on the horrors of aging and parenthood and all the things that I couldn’t hope to relate to in the eighth grade. And did I mention that none of the characters are writers?&lt;/p&gt;
</content></entry></feed>